Abijah J. Ford

ford.abijah@gmail.com | C: 651-468-9313

2259 Marion St, Roseville, MN 55113

Summary

Versatile Full-Stack developer with 3 years of schooling with roughly 2 years of programming on projects outside of school. I have experience designing, developing, and managing a local organizations site and internal frameworks.

Coding Languages

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, C#, PHP, jQuery, ReactJS, SQL, Node, and Python

Skills

- Communication/Public Speaking
- Time Management/Planning
- Deep understanding of technology
- Open-mindedness
- Learning/Adaptability
- Problem-Solving
- **Client Relations**

Education

Century Community College, White Bear Lake, MN

2020

Associate in Science Computer Science and Computer

Information Systems 3.30 GPA

Certificates Internet Programming 3.40 GPA

Member Computer Science Club

Work History

WordPress Developer

Living Word Church – St. Paul, MN

02/2021 - Present

- Created trusted relationships with the staff members
- Designed the website using WordPress, HTML, APIs, JS, and CSS
- Maintaining the webpage and updating it as needed

Teacher

Tech Academy – St. Paul, MN

05/2019 - 09/2019

- Administered lectures and tutorials on topics such as: Programming, Engineering, and Hydroponics
- Programmed Java based applications with a class of 15+, modifying the game of Minecraft

Host/Cook

Davannis – Roseville, MN

03/2015 - 06/2019

- Answered phones to plan party room reservations accordingly
- Trained newcomers/employees
- Prepared orders and made sure they were up to customers standards

Delivery Driver Expert Dominos – Little Canada, MN

06/2019 - 06/2021

- Operated delivery vehicle in a safe and efficient manner
- Selected optimal routes in compliance with delivery instructions to meet tight deadlines